<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-20T23:13:33+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Joshua Hackett</title><subtitle>I'm a journalist, digital content producer &amp; coder based in London.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Three steps to learn to code, as a complete beginner</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/18/how-to-start-coding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three steps to learn to code, as a complete beginner" /><published>2017-08-19T00:35:20+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-19T00:35:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/18/how-to-start-coding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/18/how-to-start-coding.html">&lt;p&gt;There was a time where all you needed was a program like Dreamweaver and a domain name, and you could learn all there was to know about web development in a few days. Unfortunately, that’s no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web development is now an incredibly diverse, active field, with new tricks and gadgets coming out daily and abandoned just as quickly. Professional web developers use a formidable mix of frameworks and tools that’s daunting to beginners. It’s easy to become paralysed by indecision - what should I learn first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, as coding itself becomes more varied, the resources available to total beginners are also better than ever. Best of all, most of these &lt;strong&gt;don’t cost a penny&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the three stages of learning I went through over the past four years, taking me from a complete novice who’d never written a line of code to someone comfortable with a range of modern web technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stage-1-learn-your-first-language-with-interactive-lessons&quot;&gt;Stage 1: Learn your first language with interactive lessons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; is one of a growing number of sites which offer free, basic courses in a variety of coding languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a powerful tool for learning because it’s &lt;em&gt;interactive&lt;/em&gt;. If you make a mistake, it’s easy to work out exactly how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sites that offer only non-interactive video lessons often stump complete beginners - learners might have different software versions to an instructor, and get frustrated when things don’t work as described. Codecademy avoids this problem with a code editor and preview right there in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/coding_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Codecademy interface makes it difficult to get stuck.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic HTML and CSS courses are a great place to start. While you can’t build a full-fledged web application with HTML and CSS alone, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; produce great looking websites, and knowing HTML and CSS is a vital prerequisite for learning a ‘proper’ language like PHP, Javascript or Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve learned those basics, Javascript is as good as any language to learn next. It’s Javascript that enables the rich interactive experiences we’ve become used to on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this early stage, it doesn’t really matter what languages you learn. Modern programming languages have a lot of shared features (loops, variables, functions and so on), so no matter what your first language is, you’ll find it easier to learn your second, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also find that you make quick progress - you should be able to blast through a few of these courses over a weekend or a few evenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stage-2-get-stuck-in-with-projects-and-tutorials&quot;&gt;Stage 2: Get stuck in with projects and tutorials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn the basics of a programming language in a matter of hours. Once you have that down, the next stage is to apply that understanding to real-world projects. That means tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are new to self-directed learning, take some time to consider whether you learn best from written articles or video lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/coding_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Youtube channels like DevTips and Mackenzie Child offer a suite of instructional videos targeted at beginners.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be that you’re learning to code with a particular objective in mind. Perhaps you want to sell something, advertise an organisation, or re-do an existing site? Personally, my initial objective was to learn enough to create a Wordpress theme for my student newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an objective set out, you should seek out tutorials that relate to it. You might even find a tutorial that accomplishes exactly what you want to do. If you can’t, don’t worry, because every tutorial will expand your knowledge in a way you can apply to your later work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;You may even run across people who are surprised you're not using the latest cutting-edge framework or tool in your work. Ignore these people.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation often flags during this stage. The quick results and ‘aha’ moments of learning a new language for the first time don’t happen as often. It’s vital to go at your own pace and only do tutorials you find fun or interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can keep your motivation up by exploring at the work of others. Publications like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativebloq.com/net-magazine&quot;&gt;Net magazine&lt;/a&gt;, and podcasts like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/bigwebshow&quot;&gt;Big Web Show&lt;/a&gt; showcase a diversity of successful web projects, and can help you avoid getting stuck in a rut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your pace, this stage might last a few weeks, to a few months, to upwards of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it’s important to keep a sense of perspective. Web development has only been around for just over a decade. It’s an incredibly fast-moving industry, with a ton of new frameworks, tools, trends released every month. Try not to be overwhelmed and distracted by all the noise: focus on your own goals and learning plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stage-3-research-problems-the-smart-way-and-start-gaining-experience&quot;&gt;Stage 3: Research problems the smart way and start gaining experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, you’ll stop following tutorials by rote and start working on your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find that you stop relying on other people’s instructions and more on your own ingenuity. You’ll also find that the problems you have to solve will be bigger, and won’t throw up as many easily-googled answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to solve common errors like “why is my CSS not working” or “what does Wordpress ‘Error establishing database connection’ mean”, but once you strike out on your own, &lt;strong&gt;the whole process is one big problem to be solved&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find that as you gain experience, your problems will become less like “How do I…” and more like “What’s the &lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt; way to do…”. In web development, there are often many ways to address a particular challenge, and creating good code is understanding which solution is the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encountering problems can be very frustrating as a beginner, but once you get to this stage, you’ll start to enjoy thinking your way around each challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the best measure of your ability as a coder isn’t knowledge - it’s &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sites like StackOverflow and Github will become your best friend. There’s no shame in keeping forums and reference material close by while you code. No one’s brain is big enough to hold an entire language or framework in their head, no matter what they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/coding_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;StackOverflow and Github are two great resources for coders of all kinds.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popular culture version of a computer programmer - someone who works in isolation, hammering away on their keyboard - is a myth. In real life, coding is a collaborative, social activity, and people who lean on the experience and ideas of those around them generally make better coders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all to say that you should consider web development a community. Listen to podcasts, read articles, follow other developers on social media. If you have the opportunity, go to a conference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to what other coders have to say is the best way to stay up to date, and to make sure that you never stop learning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">There was a time where all you needed was a program like Dreamweaver and a domain name, and you could learn all there was to know about web development in a few days. Unfortunately, that’s no longer the case.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/coding_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Common - NT’s new epic stays firmly stuck to the ground</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/06/02/common.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Common - NT's new epic stays firmly stuck to the ground" /><published>2017-06-02T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/06/02/common</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/06/02/common.html">&lt;p&gt;The star occupant of the NT’s Olivier Theatre for the next few months is &lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt;, a co-production with the lauded Headlong Theatre which bills itself as “an epic tale of England’s lost land”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thrust of the plot is a brewing class war over the impending Enclosure Act, which will take away the remaining common land and restrict its use to owners. Against this setting, Anne-Marie Duff’s Mary returns to the rural land of her birth, where everyone thinks her long-dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;It's a shame that Common decides to pursue the path of a cheap Game of Thrones knock-off&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It quickly turns out she’s been married and come by a fortune, and wastes no time turning the delicate standoff between the villagers and their lord to her own benefit, with both of her adoptive siblings paying a price for her unexpected return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a kernel of a good idea here. The world of &lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt; is facing down the maw of the industrial revolution. It hints at interesting, under-explored social issues around race, sexuality and gender that have no shortage of dramatic potential, and even underscore the modern issues of a post-Brexit UK. They’re a fine basis for a play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that pedigree, it’s a shame that &lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt; decides to pursue the path of a cheap &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; knock-off. It keeps the pedestrian violence, toxic relationships and sexual misbehaviour but dispenses with the intrigue and delicate world-building that made that series so compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And injects a talking crow, for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/common_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Anne-Marie Duff in rehearsals for Common. Photo: Johann Persson&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are good bits: when the villagers get their pagan masks out in order to go marauding and sacrificing, it’s genuinely creepy, especially when they turn their rage toward a familiar face at the conclusion of the play’s first half. But these moments are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after the war between the villagers and the manor turns deadly, and the plot should be driving toward the promised ambitious finale, &lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt; remains hamstrung, faltering between subplots and continuing to realign characters’ allegiances seemingly on a whim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim McMullan’s haughty lord of the manor seethes with privilege, and gets a few good speeches in early on - blood running through the land and so forth. A few awkward scene transitions later, he’s devolved into nothing more than a weak foil to Mary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite embodying yet another incarnation of the tired old “depraved bisexual” cliche, Anne-Marie Duff’s character is the best part of &lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt;. That said, even &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt; constant scheming leaves the audience unsympathetic and confused about who we should be rooting for, if anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Common&lt;/em&gt; is a tone-deaf, scrabbling attempt at an epic play, but its characters are so poorly imagined and the main action so disjointed that it falls face-first into the mud. There’s a quarter of a good play here, and represents a rare misstep for Headlong.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The star occupant of the NT’s Olivier Theatre for the next few months is Common, a co-production with the lauded Headlong Theatre which bills itself as “an epic tale of England’s lost land”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/common_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Advertise with Westminster SU</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/26/advertising-landing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advertise with Westminster SU" /><published>2017-05-26T13:00:20+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-26T13:00:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/26/advertising-landing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/26/advertising-landing.html">&lt;p&gt;As part of a large-scale redevelopment of Westminster SU’s digital platforms and services, we decided to overhaul key landing pages on the website, especially those responsible for promoting commercial initiatives like advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replacing simple text-heavy designs, these new pages benefit from bespoke art direction, incorporating animation, parallax scroll effects, interactivity and photorealistic mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular page promotes advertising packages: providing key audience statistics of the SU’s channels, offering a virtual catalogue of packages that users can click and hover through, and clear calls to action - get in touch with us or download our media pack PDF for further information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/landing_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Views of the page on a variety of viewport sizes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photorealistic mockups which animate on page scrolls offer clear indications of the services on offer, and key statistics animate in as they enter the user’s viewport, carefully guidng the user’s journey for maximal conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These pages were designed by initial consultation with the commercial team with the packages and USPs we could offer clients, followed by the creation of wireframes, content (tailored copy and imagery), and finally working mockups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">As part of a large-scale redevelopment of Westminster SU’s digital platforms and services, we decided to overhaul key landing pages on the website, especially those responsible for promoting commercial initiatives like advertising.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/landing_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Alien: Covenant - Ridley has another stab at it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/05/11/alien-covenant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alien: Covenant - Ridley has another stab at it" /><published>2017-05-11T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-11T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/05/11/alien-covenant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/05/11/alien-covenant.html">&lt;p&gt;Five years on from &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;’ high concept and flawed execution, &lt;em&gt;Alien: Covenant&lt;/em&gt; follows a colony ship carrying thousands of hibernating humans to a new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They get waylaid, of course, and the crew, which includes Katherine Waterston’s Daniels, eventually runs into Michael Fassbender’s errant android, David on a strange deserted world, ten years after he was last seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/films/news/alien-covenant-ridley-scott-prometheus-release-date-trailer-xenomorph-a7731851.html&quot;&gt;In an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Independent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, director Ridley Scott essentially admits that after the frosty reception of &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;, the iconic xenomorph was shoe-horned back in here as a convoluted form of fan-service, and it shows. &lt;em&gt;Covenant&lt;/em&gt; spends its first two acts aping the big themes and expansive locales of &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;, and its last act duplicating the claustrophobic horrors of the 1979 original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;q&gt;David's presence is the only thing lifting Covenant from mediocrity&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Synthetics have always been nearly as core to the Alien franchise as the titular creature, portrayed variously as foils and helpers to the human characters, but have never taken centre stage before now, with not one but two androids in the main cast, both played by Fassbender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is very little that modern audiences don’t know about the xenomorph - so it’s hard to keep them scary. The first film thrived on the simple &lt;em&gt;unknowable other-ness&lt;/em&gt; of the creature, but nearly four decades on, there’s very little of that left to play on. It’s good, then, that the story of &lt;em&gt;Alien: Covenant&lt;/em&gt; is really more about David and the creation of life, than the titular aliens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/covenant_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The xenomorphs have been resurrected after their conspicuous absence in Prometheus.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, David’s presence is the only thing lifting &lt;em&gt;Covenant&lt;/em&gt; from mediocrity. It’s the same move Ridley tried to pull with &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; - marrying the sci-fi body horror with Big Themes®, but in 2012, after the franchise had been on ice for so long, the move was unexpected and confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetically, the design of the &lt;em&gt;Covenant&lt;/em&gt; is halfway between the clean, high-tech, world of &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; (taking its cues from the present day), and the dirty 70s retro-future of the original film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/covenant_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Despite publicity, Katherine Waterston's Daniels is never as interesting as Fassbender's two android characters.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s generally a bad idea to rely on human stupidity to create tension, and while the bad decision-making and rough characterisation that blighted &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; aren’t gone, they are certainly more subtle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, just as in the 2012 prequel, you never quite buy into the characters’ personalities enough to see them as more than xenomorph-fodder. With the &lt;em&gt;Covenant&lt;/em&gt;’s crew of six or seven couples, there’s just too many to get to know over the course of 120 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;q&gt;We never buy into the characters' personalities enough to see them as more than xenomorph-fodder&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is loaded with the kind of poor character choices that might make sense for the blue-collar crew of the &lt;em&gt;Nostromo&lt;/em&gt;, but are bizarre and out of place for the presumably talented and trained professionals we encounter here. Billy Crudup’s captain, Oram, has an unspecified ‘faith’ which, perplexingly, the film only really uses to explain away his general incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final moments of the film rely on a twist so obvious that we end up angry at the characters for not seeing it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fairly gratuitous liberties are taken with the alien’s life cycle. While  the original films tried to at least maintain a semblance of biological realism (acidic blood notwithstanding), Covenent makes the species essentially magical - going from facehugger, to chestburster, to full-grown adult in a matter of minutes - a speed which strains suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Covenant&lt;/em&gt; is definitely a better film than &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt;, but it’d need a few more decades of hypersleep to catch up with &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Five years on from Prometheus’ high concept and flawed execution, Alien: Covenant follows a colony ship carrying thousands of hibernating humans to a new world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/covenant_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyperlog - a 24/7 utility for internet radio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/05/hyperlog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyperlog - a 24/7 utility for internet radio" /><published>2017-05-05T13:00:20+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T13:00:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/05/hyperlog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/ux/2017/05/05/hyperlog.html">&lt;p&gt;In most localities, radio stations must maintain a complete log of their on-air output. Advertisers and station staff may also wish to monitor broadcast output, and presenters are increasingly seeking easy ways to make their shows available to a wider audience as podcasts. Therefore, radio logging software was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, traditional logging software must run on specialist hardware and needs a direct audio input from a live studio. Industry-standard solutions are prohibitively expensive for community and student radio stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, Hyperlog is the only cloud-based audio logger: it listens only to what is actually broadcast, so it can run on any server anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hyperlog_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Hyperlog user interface.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyperlog is a web application based on node.js. It runs 24/7 on the recording server and is accessible via any web browser. It makes regular hourly recordings of broadcast output, and can also log the metadata of each hour, by making a request to the API of the radio station’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recordings can then be perused using the browser UI. Metadata like show name, description and genre is attached to each recording, and each can be downloaded. It also has a simple read-only API to integrate with a station’s other online services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The administrator can specify a maximum number of hours to archive (eg. one week, one month), at which point Hyperlog will begin deleting the oldest recordings. In most localities, regulators require a 30-day log to be retained.  Important recordings can be “pinned” to prevent automatic deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next iteration of Hyperlog will integrate with third party services like Mixcloud, Audioboom and Soundcloud, enabling automatic uploading of radio shows so they can be promoted and shared as podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">In most localities, radio stations must maintain a complete log of their on-air output. Advertisers and station staff may also wish to monitor broadcast output, and presenters are increasingly seeking easy ways to make their shows available to a wider audience as podcasts. Therefore, radio logging software was born.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/hyperlog_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Westminster SU impact report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/04/10/impact-report.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Westminster SU impact report" /><published>2017-04-11T00:35:20+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-11T00:35:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/04/10/impact-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/04/10/impact-report.html">&lt;p&gt;While at Westminster Students’ Union, I was tasked with making an online version of the organisation’s annual impact report, which is normally distributed in print format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/impactreport_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The report is divided into scrollable sections, with a strong branded colour scheme.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the content from the print version of the report, rewriting copy for a web audience where needed, teasing out key statistics and drawing simple icons and vector illustrations to accompany the stats. After assembling the content, I moved onto wireframes and sketch mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I coded the concept from the ground-up, incorporating SVG animations, Javascript-driven interactivity, pie and bar charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/impactreport_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I began, as always, with content, followed by wireframes and mockups.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interactive, animated graphs were developed for the report using the popular D3.js (Data Driven Documents) library. These respond to the user’s cursor or touch interaction and are fully mobile-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">While at Westminster Students’ Union, I was tasked with making an online version of the organisation’s annual impact report, which is normally distributed in print format.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/impactreport_2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ghost in the Shell: Stunning but simplistic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/31/ghost-in-the-shell.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ghost in the Shell: Stunning but simplistic" /><published>2017-03-31T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-31T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/31/ghost-in-the-shell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/31/ghost-in-the-shell.html">&lt;p&gt;Willing suspension of disbelief means audiences will accept the outright impossible, but they’re less likely to forgive what they know to be simply improbable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the idea that in a few decades most positions of power in Japan will be held by white people strains credibility &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; than the prospect of implanting a human brain into a robotic body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;The themes of the original anime are simplified for a Western audience.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s adaptation of the seminal &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt; anime, starring Scarlett Johansson as a cybernetically-enhanced crimefighter known as the Major, courted early controversy over perceived white-washing of Asian roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience is made dimly aware of a massive influx of Western refugees to the film’s near-future cyberpunk version of Japan, presumably due to some reversal of fortunes overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the fact that the Major - a Japanese woman working for the Japanese government, is being played by Scarlett Johanssen, proves to be a plot point of sorts, does not fully excuse this, especially since there are barely a handful of Asian speaking roles in the whole film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/gits_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Several scenes are shot-fot-shot recreations of the anime.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adaptation simplifies the themes and plot threads of the source material for a more demanding Western audience. This isn’t necessarily a bad thing, as it brings a new focus to the Major’s personal struggle and her emotional turmoil, and brings a much-needed human dimension to the philosophising of the source material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the process, a lot of the ambiguity and thematic textures which made the original anime so beloved are left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, part of the appeal of Mamoru Oshii’s 1995 anime was the subtlety of its portrayal of technology. In this adaptation, cybernetics are closely allied to corporate corruption and destruction. Big bad Hanka Robotics may as well be &lt;em&gt;Robocop&lt;/em&gt;’s OCP or &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;’s Weyland-Yutani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The corporate corruption angle is done to death in Western sci-fi (take James Cameron’s &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt; as examples), but feels weirdly tacked on here, though it’s certainly necessary to bring a more accessible, singular villain to the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/gits_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;'Visually speaking, the film is impeccable.'&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is unapologetically about Johansson’s character. Of the supporting cast, only Pilou Asbæk’s Batou and Takeshi Kitano’s Chief Aramaki get a chance to prove their worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;The neon-soaked high-rise world of this year's Ghost in the Shell is genuinely stunning to look at&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clint Mansell and Lorne Balfe’s near-perfect score is an enticing blend of the original anime’s haunting chorals and the 80s synths we’re familiar with from Mansell’s work on &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;’s memorable ‘San Junipero’ episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt; pays no shortage of tributes to its source anime. Some scenes are shot-for-shot recreations of scenes from the original anime. Even a beagle makes it in - a Mamoru Oshii signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neon-soaked high-rise world of this year’s &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt; is genuinely stunning to look at, and the film rightfully strips down the plot to focus on the individual drama of Johansson’s character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, without the philosophical musings that so defined the source material, it’s easy to feel that the soul - or “ghost” - of the franchise has been lost along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Willing suspension of disbelief means audiences will accept the outright impossible, but they’re less likely to forgive what they know to be simply improbable.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/gits_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life - A creepy-crawly space station nightmare</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life - A creepy-crawly space station nightmare" /><published>2017-03-24T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-24T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life.html">&lt;p&gt;As we send out probe after probe specifically intended to hunt for life beyond earth, it doesn’t seem as unlikely as it once did that we might actually find some.  So it’s an appropriate time for flicks like &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt;, which imagine what might happen if that life turns out to be not so friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near future, a space probe carrying precious Martian samples is grabbed by a souped-up international space station, and the six-astronaut crew investigate the traces of life aboard, keeping it quarantined in the relative isolation of the orbiting laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named Calvin by school kids back on earth, the cells begin to reanimate, and grow alarmingly fast. It goes downhill from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; tries, with varying success, to mix the body horror and claustrophobia of &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; with the high-octane zero-gee excitement of &lt;em&gt;Gravity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; and other modern orbital thrill-rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the tropes are firmly in place: tracking an unknown terror on motion sensors, limited weaponry, astronauts being picked off one by one. Even the typography of the opening title is shamelessly lifted from Ridley Scott’s classics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international space station is an intriguing setting, taking inspiration from the present-day station and bulking it up considerably to reflect a decade or so of future expansion. The passageways, nooks and crannies lend themselves so perfectly to this kind of suspenseful horror it’s a wonder no one’s thought of it before. There’s clear attention to detail in the design of the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/life_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gyllenhaal gets the most to do of the six astronauts, but we never really get to know him.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The astronauts remain paper-thin sketches, with just enough personality added into the mix to make them believable, but viewers will struggle to name a single character hours after leaving the cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the nature of the sci-fi horror genre that the characters are scientists - presumably well-trained, level-headed professionals. Yet, those characters &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to fail gratuitously: blundering into quarantine zones, making all the wrong choices, simply in order to drive the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a balancing act that 2013’s &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; got completely wrong, for instance. It’s better executed here - just well enough to keep you believing that these ISS astronauts do actually know what they’re doing ninety per cent of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is finely-strung and genuinely suspenseful, but only really comes into its own once it makes it clear that the extraterrestrial Calvin won’t be defeated by conventional means. After all, even Ripley eventually managed to dispatch &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;’s xenomorph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And without spoilers, the bait and switch coming into play for the film’s final scene is masterful, finally delivering on the potential the film had been holding back to that point. It’s the closing moments which make &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; worth the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">As we send out probe after probe specifically intended to hunt for life beyond earth, it doesn’t seem as unlikely as it once did that we might actually find some.  So it’s an appropriate time for flicks like Life, which imagine what might happen if that life turns out to be not so friendly.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/life_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sleeping Giants - Equal parts alien robots and political intrigue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sleeping Giants - Equal parts alien robots and political intrigue" /><published>2017-03-05T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-05T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants.html">&lt;p&gt;Ten year old Rose falls down a hole. Rescuers find her in the palm of a half-buried enormous metal hand, which proceeds to baffle all experts until a now-adult Rose is put back on the case by a mysterious financier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More body parts are eventually discovered, and as they are collected, it becomes clear that they are all pieces of a single machine (a hand or a head might be independent objects of veneration, but a thigh?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the extraterrestrial nature of the find becomes clear, a tale of political intrigue and conspiracies emerges as various parties seek to weaponise the robot, eventually pushing the world to the brink of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central gimmick of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is that is told in an interview format, all conducted by a nameless, near-omniscient interviewer. Though their identity remains shady throughout, we come to realise they are the only one who has any real idea what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;As the extraterrestrial nature of the find becomes clear, a tale of political intrigue and conspiracies emerges.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greater plot momentum toward the end of the book means it begins to labour under the weight of this narrative mechanism: the interview format does not lend itself well to fight scenes, for instance. These scenes just about hold together with a healthy dose of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, the story of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is as genre as genre fiction gets. The premise of an enormous robot, piloted by a psychologically attuned duo, engineered to fight hand-to-hand with a presumably equally large foe, is certainly borrowed from &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/giants_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;'Artwork: '&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters too are sci-fi archetypes. Dr Rose Franklin is one more version of the multidisciplinary brainbox scientist descended from Mr Spock and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Carter&quot;&gt;SG-1’s Samantha Carter&lt;/a&gt;, somehow equally comfortable with molecular genetics and mechanical engineering. Kara Resnik owes much to the hard-talking, no-nonsense women pilots from &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt; all the way through to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kara_Thrace&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battlestar Galactica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these trite beginnings, the real  achievement of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is how author Sylvain Neuvel brings these archetypes to life. Their actions and relationships are totally convincing, despite us never seeing them interact with anyone except the interviewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;The celluloid practically jumps off the page.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is the debut novel you wish you’d written, if only you’d had the courage to move beyond all that fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it pays a heavy debt to genre convention, &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; mixes in just enough originality to make it a compelling joy to read - giddy with the possibilities of its own universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, a film adaptation is imminent. The celluloid practically jumps off the page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Ten year old Rose falls down a hole. Rescuers find her in the palm of a half-buried enormous metal hand, which proceeds to baffle all experts until a now-adult Rose is put back on the case by a mysterious financier.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/giants_2.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A live broadcast graphics engine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/video/ux/2017/02/09/A-live-motion-graphics-engine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A live broadcast graphics engine" /><published>2017-02-09T23:35:20+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-09T23:35:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/video/ux/2017/02/09/A-live-motion-graphics-engine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/video/ux/2017/02/09/A-live-motion-graphics-engine.html">&lt;p&gt;Brooker CG (character generator) is a tool designed to make broadcast-quality graphics easy and straightforward to achieve for student television volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional character generation hardware and software is prohibitively expensive, and the other alternative - using software like Adobe After Effects to render out all graphics in advance, is time-consuming and requires a great deal of forward planning to do effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brooker CG application allows a volunteer to use simple text input fields to create custom graphics on the fly, updating viewers with alert messages, scrolling tickers, scoreboards and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/brooker_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Brooker CG control panel.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application relies on a Websockets server written in node.js, and accepts commands issued from a browser control panel. It is compatible with all major video live streaming software, including Wirecast and Open Broadcast Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future versions of Brooker CG will incorporate live infographics, charts and direct integration with social media feeds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Brooker CG (character generator) is a tool designed to make broadcast-quality graphics easy and straightforward to achieve for student television volunteers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/brooker_1.jpg" /></entry></feed>
