<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-26T02:21:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Joshua Hackett</title><subtitle>I'm a journalist, digital content producer &amp; coder based in London.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Life - A creepy-crawly space station nightmare</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life - A creepy-crawly space station nightmare" /><published>2017-03-24T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-24T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/24/life.html">&lt;p&gt;As we send out probe after probe specifically intended to hunt for life beyond earth, it doesn’t seem as unlikely as it once did that we might actually find some.  So it’s an appropriate time for flicks like &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt;, which imagine what might happen if that life turns out to be not so friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near future, a space probe carrying precious Martian samples is grabbed by a souped-up international space station, and the six-astronaut crew investigate the traces of life aboard, keeping it quarantined in the relative isolation of the orbiting laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named Calvin by school kids back on earth, the cells begin to reanimate, and grow alarmingly fast. It goes downhill from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; tries, with varying success, to mix the body horror and claustrophobia of &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; with the high-octane zero-gee excitement of &lt;em&gt;Gravity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; and other modern orbital thrill-rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the tropes are firmly in place: tracking an unknown terror on motion sensors, limited weaponry, astronauts being picked off one by one. Even the typography of the opening title is shamelessly lifted from Ridley Scott’s classics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international space station is an intriguing setting, taking inspiration from the present-day station and bulking it up considerably to reflect a decade or so of future expansion. The passageways, nooks and crannies lend themselves so perfectly to this kind of suspenseful horror it’s a wonder no one’s thought of it before. There’s clear attention to detail in the design of the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/life_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gyllenhaal gets the most to do of the six astronauts, but we never really get to know him.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The astronauts remain paper-thin sketches, with just enough personality added into the mix to make them believable, but viewers will struggle to name a single character hours after leaving the cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the nature of the sci-fi horror genre that the characters are scientists - presumably well-trained, level-headed professionals. Yet, those characters &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to fail gratuitously: blundering into quarantine zones, making all the wrong choices, simply in order to drive the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a balancing act that 2013’s &lt;em&gt;Prometheus&lt;/em&gt; got completely wrong, for instance. It’s better executed here - just well enough to keep you believing that these ISS astronauts do actually know what they’re doing ninety per cent of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is finely-strung and genuinely suspenseful, but only really comes into its own once it makes it clear that the extraterrestrial Calvin won’t be defeated by conventional means. After all, even Ripley eventually managed to dispatch &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;’s xenomorph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And without spoilers, the bait and switch coming into play for the film’s final scene is masterful, finally delivering on the potential the film had been holding back to that point. It’s the closing moments which make &lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; worth the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">As we send out probe after probe specifically intended to hunt for life beyond earth, it doesn’t seem as unlikely as it once did that we might actually find some.  So it’s an appropriate time for flicks like Life, which imagine what might happen if that life turns out to be not so friendly.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/life_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sleeping Giants - Equal parts alien robots and political intrigue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sleeping Giants - Equal parts alien robots and political intrigue" /><published>2017-03-05T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-05T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2017/03/05/sleeping-giants.html">&lt;p&gt;Ten year old Rose falls down a hole. Rescuers find her in the palm of a half-buried enormous metal hand, which proceeds to baffle all experts until a now-adult Rose is put back on the case by a mysterious financier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More body parts are eventually discovered, and as they are collected, it becomes clear that they are all pieces of a single machine (a hand or a head might be independent objects of veneration, but a thigh?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the extraterrestrial nature of the find becomes clear, a tale of political intrigue and conspiracies emerges as various parties seek to weaponise the robot, eventually pushing the world to the brink of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central gimmick of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is that is told in an interview format, all conducted by a nameless, near-omniscient interviewer. Though their identity remains shady throughout, we come to realise they are the only one who has any real idea what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;As the extraterrestrial nature of the find becomes clear, a tale of political intrigue and conspiracies emerges.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greater plot momentum toward the end of the book means it begins to labour under the weight of this narrative mechanism: the interview format does not lend itself well to fight scenes, for instance. These scenes just about hold together with a healthy dose of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its face, the story of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is as genre as genre fiction gets. The premise of an enormous robot, piloted by a psychologically attuned duo, engineered to fight hand-to-hand with a presumably equally large foe, is certainly borrowed from &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/giants_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;'Artwork: '&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters too are sci-fi archetypes. Dr Rose Franklin is one more version of the multidisciplinary brainbox scientist descended from Mr Spock and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samantha_Carter&quot;&gt;SG-1’s Samantha Carter&lt;/a&gt;, somehow equally comfortable with molecular genetics and mechanical engineering. Kara Resnik owes much to the hard-talking, no-nonsense women pilots from &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt; all the way through to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kara_Thrace&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battlestar Galactica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these trite beginnings, the real  achievement of &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is how author Sylvain Neuvel brings these archetypes to life. Their actions and relationships are totally convincing, despite us never seeing them interact with anyone except the interviewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;q&gt;The celluloid practically jumps off the page.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; is the debut novel you wish you’d written, if only you’d had the courage to move beyond all that fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it pays a heavy debt to genre convention, &lt;em&gt;Sleeping Giants&lt;/em&gt; mixes in just enough originality to make it a compelling joy to read - giddy with the possibilities of its own universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, a film adaptation is imminent. The celluloid practically jumps off the page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Ten year old Rose falls down a hole. Rescuers find her in the palm of a half-buried enormous metal hand, which proceeds to baffle all experts until a now-adult Rose is put back on the case by a mysterious financier.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/giants_2.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Smoke Radio broadcast rebuild</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/02/09/Smoke-radio-broadcast-rebuild.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smoke Radio broadcast rebuild" /><published>2017-02-09T23:35:20+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-09T23:35:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/02/09/Smoke-radio-broadcast-rebuild</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/02/09/Smoke-radio-broadcast-rebuild.html">&lt;p&gt;Smoke Radio is one of the top student radio stations in the UK, involving nearly one hundred students every year and broadcasting 24/7. They took home the Student Radio Association’s award for best station in 2015, and were shortlisted again in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I became student media coordinator in early 2016, the station was facing several issues with its broadcast infrastructure. The media server being used relied on Flash, which has virtually no mobile support and rapidly declining desktop support. This massively limited the potential audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The station operates across all four of the University of Westminster’ campuses, with studios in central London and up in Harrow. However, taking a different studio live was time-consuming and difficult, so rarely done, again limiting participation and membership on particular campuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/radio_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Smoke Radio's implementation of the Airtime system.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replaced the existing proprietary media server with two pieces of open-source software. For basic streaming, I went with Icecast, which is the gold standard for audio webcasting. It supports MP3 as well as higher efficiency codecs like AAC, and does not rely on Flash. This streaming protocol is also compatible with hardware audio decoders, and these are now being obtained and installed in social areas on campus, to improve listenership and brand awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icecast was controlled by the second piece of software, Airtime. Airtime functions as a central scheduling and playout manager. Media can be uploaded and connections to various studios established, and so live shows, pre-recorded shows and outside broadcasts can be made according to a single central calendar. Switchover became automated and hassle-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These upgrades also laid crucial groundwork for a cross-platform mobile app for on-the-go listening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Smoke Radio is one of the top student radio stations in the UK, involving nearly one hundred students every year and broadcasting 24/7. They took home the Student Radio Association’s award for best station in 2015, and were shortlisted again in 2016.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/radio_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Smoke Media website rebrand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/01/24/Smoke-media-website-rebrand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smoke Media website rebrand" /><published>2017-01-24T23:35:20+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-24T23:35:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/01/24/Smoke-media-website-rebrand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/digital/2017/01/24/Smoke-media-website-rebrand.html">&lt;p&gt;As part of my role as student media coordinator, I initiated a ground-up rebuild of &lt;a href=&quot;'http://smoke.media'&quot;&gt;Smoke Media’s&lt;/a&gt; web presence in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I began work, Smoke’s web presence was disparate, consisting of a Youtube channel, two aged and dissimilar Wordpress sites, and a free Wix site. All used out-of-the-box templates with minimal customisation. Most importantly, all were very different from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my strategic priorities was to shift Smoke Media from a print-first to a digital-first organisation, reflecting the shift going on in the wider world. It was also vital to communicate a single, converged brand to our audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met with student stakeholders to come up with a feature set and compile design ideas for the new website. I introduced students to a common web design progress: &lt;strong&gt;brief, wireframe, mockups, prototypes and product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very important that the new site automate common tasks such as the uploading of electronic versions of print publications, a process which involved many manual, tedious steps. Integration with external services such as Youtube, Audioboom and a number of custom in-house APIs was also necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/smoke_media_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The website combines content and functionality from Westminster SU's student-led radio &amp;amp; TV station, newspaper and magazine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than using Wordpress multisite or completely seperate websites to give the impression of convergence while still being seperate under the bonnet, the new Smoke website makes clever use of customised category pages and custom fields to offer a multimedia experience which is met by few other student media groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student media volunteers can replace a default featured image with a video or piece of audio, allowing for easy collaborations between outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A custom post type &lt;strong&gt;live events&lt;/strong&gt; allows video livestreams, radio broadcast players and text liveblogs to be combined on a single topic for converged coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website automatically imports recently uploaded content to Audioboom, Youtube and Issuu, among other services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/smoke_media_1.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The website features special content sections to promote particular campaigns.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new website offers a fit-for-purpose platform for publishing content, and is the ideal springboard to bring Westminster’s two publications into the digital-first present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also enable the later development of a cross-platform mobile application, which will automatically fetch content from the website database using the Wordpress REST API.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">As part of my role as student media coordinator, I initiated a ground-up rebuild of Smoke Media’s web presence in 2016.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/work1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Review: Ugly Lies the Bone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/ugly-lies-the-bone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review: Ugly Lies the Bone" /><published>2017-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/ugly-lies-the-bone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/ugly-lies-the-bone.html">&lt;p&gt;The National Theatre’s new production follows a wounded veteran, Jess, as she returns to her family home on the Florida coast on the eve of the final space shuttle launch, and experiments with a pioneering new virtual reality therapy to heal her emotional trauma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This play is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an inspirational tale of overcoming difficult odds. But nor is it a depressing tale about how some wounds can never heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate Fleetwood, who portrays Jess, expertly treads the fine emotional line between hardened veteran and vulnerable sister - at one moment attempting to reignite a lost romance with a former boyfriend (Ralf Little), the next laying a verbal smackdown on her new deadbeat brother in law (Kris Marshall, with his best American drawl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jess and her family inhabit a drab, featureless world surrounded by steep, curved walls. All the characters’ actions take place trapped at the bottom of this literal bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an assured choice of staging which gets across Jess’ feeling of being captive in her own body well,  as well as being an astute metaphor for the economic woes afflicting the entire Space Coast as the shuttle program winds down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world only ever springs to life during Jess’ VR therapy sessions. The plain walls become a canvas for lavish outdoor scenes: from glassy lakes to snow-covered mountains. The video projection and lighting spectacular used to convey these therapy sessions is nothing short of an extravagant visual achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jess struggles to reconnect with her family and old friends, all the while taking refuge in astounding virtual wonderlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ugly_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Kate Fleetwood as Jess. Photo: Mark Douet&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It eventually becomes clear to Jess that despite its initial appeal, the virtual world has its limits. The well-meaning doctor who administers the therapy is remains unseen apart from her voice, perhaps hinting at the lack of any genuine human connection to be found in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear to the audience from the outset that the virtual world is incomplete, so it doesn’t come as much of a surprise to us when Jess catches on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ugly Lies the Bone&lt;/em&gt; fizzles away without any firm conclusion or catharsis. What message are we to take away from it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This understated ending is almost certainly a commentary on the nature of Jess’ recovery. there are no simple solutions or answers to be found - everything is a process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bit by bit, she will get better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The National Theatre’s new production follows a wounded veteran, Jess, as she returns to her family home on the Florida coast on the eve of the final space shuttle launch, and experiments with a pioneering new virtual reality therapy to heal her emotional trauma.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/ugly_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why most 360 video is no good</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/360-video.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why most 360 video is no good" /><published>2017-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/360-video</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/360-video.html">&lt;p&gt;Most 360 video you can find today falls into one of two types: it either tells a story, or conveys a sense of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conveying a mere sense of place is much easier than convincing a viewer to invest in your story. Cinematography is the set of rules that let us direct the viewer’s eye, convincing them to make that investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good videographer knows the path they want the viewer’s eyes to take through a scene, and composes their shot using stuff like the rule of thirds, leading lines and playful use of light and shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, what you leave out of a shot is just as important, if not more so, than what you leave in. Being a good photographer or videographer is all about making each shot parsimonious: knowing why it exists and framing each shot to tell a single message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 360 video upends that formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the normal rules of composition no longer apply. You can’t really direct the viewer’s eye and have no way of knowing what will be in their field of view at a given moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a 360 video of the first type — a music video with a narrative it wants you to invest in…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/91fQTXrSRZE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No real sustained close-ups, no selective focus, no framing. You could well argue that it looks a lot less immersive than conventional video, contrary to the traditional promise of 360.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, these kinds of 360 videos harken back to the early days of filmmaking, where shallow focus was rare and expensive, and directors had to fall back on old theatre blocking techniques when designing their shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directors like Wes Anderson, Stanley Kubrick and Orson Welles still make heavy use of deep focus, generally because they think it’s a better portrayal of reality. It’s more like theatre than what we now think of as filmmaking, where you don’t have as much control over where the viewer’s gaze goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/360_2.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Shining.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time, we’ll come up with new rules of composition designed expressly for the new medium of 360/VR. They’ll be based on the existing rules of videography, but not the same, just as the rules of composition we use for photography originated in those found in classical artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the closest traditional analogy to 360 is that of theatre in the round. The audience’s viewpoint and that being observed are reversed, but it’s the closest analogy we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theatre in the round is notoriously difficult to do well, because directors have to consider sight lines from all sides of the stage. It’s a lot harder to create a mise-en-scene when the normal definitions of foreground, midground and background cease to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/360_3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;'Theatre in the round'&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like at the moment, 360 video is most at home when the goal is simply to convey a sense of place — a sense of “being somewhere”. Most works of journalism produced with 360 video so far fall into this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same use case as the humble GoPro, and certainly there are many consumer 360 cameras clearly targeting the same audience. Though it’s surely been attempted, the GoPro is no one’s go-to tool for a short film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are limitations even with this less ambitious use case. Luckily, these are technical, not artistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sfVvJY-C8gA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most consumer 360 cameras still have 1080p sensors. Shared between two fisheye lenses, the end product is usually a great deal lower quality than conventional video, since there are less pixels in your field of view (FOV) at any moment, since the sensor’s pixels are being spread across the whole 360 panorama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when content is created in 4K, like the above BBC livestream, it’s still not good enough for a seamless VR effect. It looks like we’ll have to wait for even higher-resolution sensors to meet the promise of “as if you were there” 360/VR video. Compression applied by Facebook and Youtube when sharing doesn’t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s without even thinking of the problem of network connections. The UK’s average broadband download speed is currently around 22mbps, but there’s still no shortage of households which still can’t manage to download a 4k quality video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While 4G cell speeds are generally plenty fast enough for 4K, data caps definitely aren’t. A few ten minute 4K videos will burn through the monthly limit without blinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the chief complaints about VR video is that it always looks so soft. Early headsets were stuck with dismal displays, but more modern headsets like the Vive have improved. There’s a lot of work to be done on resolution, but low quality video is an increasingly important barrier to immersion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/360_4.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The HTC Vive.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this certainly isn’t a condemnation of 360 video. It’s less than five years old, and conventional video has been around for nearly a century. Any new technology needs to be given time to develop its niche and for us to learn how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s likely that the technical hurdles with 360 will be solved long before a new formal artistic “grammar” emerges for the medium. After all, the rule of thirds was only named in the 1700s, even though it was being used in artwork for centuries before that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Most 360 video you can find today falls into one of two types: it either tells a story, or conveys a sense of place.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/360_1.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Re-imagining Smoke Mag</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/Smoke-mag-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Re-imagining Smoke Mag" /><published>2016-09-02T00:35:20+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T00:35:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/Smoke-mag-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/Smoke-mag-design.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smoke Mag&lt;/em&gt; used to be a termly publication. It was printed A4 format, and was normally designed by a full-time designer. Content also overlapped heavily with student newspaper &lt;em&gt;the QH&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project was to return to basics, using audience research to build a fit-for-purpose student magazine which looked professional, had a clear remit and which was easy for student volunteers to assemble every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mag_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Each section has its own distinctive colour palette.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at a 28-page A5 magazine, published monthly. The magazine contains comment, music, lifestyle, fashion and arts sections, each with its own distinctive colour. The design is deliberately modular, so that students with minimal design training can customise it to fit their purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Smoke Mag used to be a termly publication. It was printed A4 format, and was normally designed by a full-time designer. Content also overlapped heavily with student newspaper the QH.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/mag_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Quintin Hogg redesign</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/QH-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quintin Hogg redesign" /><published>2016-09-02T00:35:20+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T00:35:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/QH-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/print/design/2016/09/01/QH-design.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Quintin Hogg&lt;/em&gt; newspaper is the latest in a long tradition of student publications at the University of Westminster. It focuses on news, current affairs and sport, and is complemented by sister publication &lt;em&gt;Smoke Mag&lt;/em&gt;, which focuses on culture and lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The redesign was conducted over summer and was intended to be a complete departure from the previous look. This was partly for simple modernisation, but also an opportunity to bring the &lt;em&gt;QH&lt;/em&gt; in line with new joint student media brand guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/qh_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The new-look QH features a no-nonsense news section with strong brand colour presence.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tabloid format was selected for convenience and cost, and a unique, modern tabloid look was developed, making use of bold headlines and crossheads, colourful pullquotes and strong presence of brand colours. A five-column grid was selected for all pages, to avoid the mishmash of designs that had afflicted earlier incarnations of the &lt;em&gt;QH&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new templates are interpreted by student volunteers, who adapt and remix them when producing each issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Quintin Hogg newspaper is the latest in a long tradition of student publications at the University of Westminster. It focuses on news, current affairs and sport, and is complemented by sister publication Smoke Mag, which focuses on culture and lifestyle.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/qh_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Field Day - The Good and the Bad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/06/13/field-day-good-and-bad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Field Day - The Good and the Bad" /><published>2016-06-13T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-13T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/06/13/field-day-good-and-bad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/06/13/field-day-good-and-bad.html">&lt;p&gt;Rainclouds, crowds and feathers, oh my. Victoria Park’s somewhat misnamed Field Day festival brings together alt and indie artists over two days and half a dozen stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City centre festivals always bring particular challenges, since there’s no campsite to build the community spirit they rely on. What’s a festivalgoer to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-good&quot;&gt;The good&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Masked Swedish world-fusion act Goat&lt;/strong&gt;. Since they gyrated onto the scene in 2013, as Glastonbury took a punt on the unknown collective, they’ve grown and grown. Not bad for a gang of stoners from Gothenberg. The masks probably help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday headliner PJ Harvey’s music&lt;/strong&gt; is nothing short of haunting, but her performance adds an extra dimension to the tunes. As she plumbs her back-catalogue, she flits between the stage personas that originally made her famous. These multiple personalities are expressed in dance, voice, gesture, and you’re in no doubt when she moves from one to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PJ Harvey’s feathers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/field_day_2.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;PJ Harvey at Field Day 2016.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This one’s dedicated to everyone who has an iPhone and isn’t currently on it”, Swedish electro-popster Molly Nilsson says during her stripped down set. &lt;strong&gt;Smartphones&lt;/strong&gt; may not encourage the transcendent, pure musical experience festivals sell us tickets on, but they must be good otherwise we wouldn’t all have them. So by that logic, being able to go home and charge them every night must be good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No one has brought wellies.&lt;/strong&gt; No one. Despite being able to check the weather forecast in the morning and access a normal wardrobe. For the select few who did choose appropriate footwear, this presents an opportunity. You get free reign over the muddier parts of the arena — usually the shortest routes from place to place. Enjoy: you’re practically a god in these parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The toilets.&lt;/strong&gt; They aren’t quite as disgusting as a countryside festival, so it counts as a win!
What’s this? Enough benches and tables for festivalgoers to actually sit down on while they eat/drink/consume? You mean we don’t have to squat in the mud? Surely you’re joking, Mr Feynman. Glastonbury could learn a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bad&quot;&gt;The bad&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have never known true fury until you have seen a press photographer cover a festival headliner with &lt;strong&gt;an iPhone and a vintage film SLR&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DJs.&lt;/strong&gt; DJs everywhere. It’s like East London has run out of bars, clubs and pubs and needs to conjure up more stages to keep them in headphones and vinyl. DJs between acts, DJs on bandstands, DJs in tucked away corners of the arena playing to each other. DJs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/field_day_3.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It’s easy to forget you aren’t in a field in the middle of nowhere. Photo: Carolina Faruolo &amp;amp; Linn Koch-Emmery.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The price.&lt;/strong&gt; Say what you will about Field Day, but it certainly gives value for money. The calibre of the acts are impressive given tickets are a mere £50 for a day and £99 for the weekend, at a time where larger festivals are pushing £250 for their weekend offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the music ends, you remember this is the centre of London and you don’t have a tent, so you find yourself either handing your life savings over to Uber or making the most of your transport knowledge to find a route home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The panicked journey&lt;/strong&gt; to get back before last tubes when you realise you already gave your life savings to your landlord, because you live in London. Almost makes you long for camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visit the Field Day website at: http://fielddayfestivals.com/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Rainclouds, crowds and feathers, oh my. Victoria Park’s somewhat misnamed Field Day festival brings together alt and indie artists over two days and half a dozen stages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/field_day_1.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Taming of the Shrew - A modern take on an uncomfortable script</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2016/06/11/taming-shrew.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Taming of the Shrew - A modern take on an uncomfortable script" /><published>2016-06-12T00:35:20+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-12T00:35:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2016/06/11/taming-shrew</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/review/2016/06/11/taming-shrew.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s always interesting to see directors try to reframe Shakespeare’s words to fit in with modern ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Globe’s most recent take on the Taming of the Shrew is an exercise in just that. It’s a more realistic, emotional take on a script that is fabulously misogynist to modern eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any performance of Taming of the Shrew — a fairly accurate tale of Elizabethan Stockholm Syndrome where an unruly young woman, Elizabeth, “tamed” by new husband Petrucio— presents a choice for the director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you address the themes with traditional British light-heartedness? Treat Katherine’s ordeal as a bit of a joke to be laughed about in the closing scenes? Or, do you face the play’s problems head on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As society becomes more aware of feminist issues, we are at a watershed moment for this play. We no longer endure entrenched sexism, and even the Bard needs to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in early-20th century Ireland, the classical surroundings belie how much of an update the play has actually been given. With shades of Beckett, director Caroline Byrne uses bleak, twisted, almost apocalyptic sets to underscore the depths of Katherine’s mistreatment at the hands of Petrucio, leaving the audience in no doubt that what they are seeing is psychological torture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aoife Duffin’s turn as the beleaguered Katherine is inspired; she brings just the right amount of confident swagger, poise and elegance to the role. The musical interludes give the audience a chance to empathise with her through her rich, yet raw, voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward MacLiam’s outright villainous portrayal of Katherine’s spouse, Petrucio, is an appropriate vessel for a masculinity in crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/shrew_2.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lucentio and Bianca. Photo: Johan Persson.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Dieffenbacher’s well-executed physical comedy, channeled mainly through the double-act of noble suitor Lucentio and his servant Tranio, adds some joyful levity to an otherwise staunch production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything hangs together well right up to the final scenes. As Katherine gives her final speech, having become the model, obedient spouse, we feel a mixture of relief, sadness and grief for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t know much about the Bard, but we know he a man was ahead of his time in most ways. So, we can hope that Caroline Byrne’s production is a truer portrayal of what he tried to put down on paper than most other directors have attempted in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Taming of the Shrew is at Shakespeare’s Globe until July.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">It’s always interesting to see directors try to reframe Shakespeare’s words to fit in with modern ideas.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/shrew_1.jpeg" /></entry></feed>
